Guide to the Elizabeth Shepley Sergeant Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1903-65; Series I; 3.5; (9 boxes)
  - Goodrich, Henriette, 1933-45, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Gregory, Alyse, 1926-55 (Box 2, Folder 61-63)
  - Gregory, Alyse, 1956-65, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 64-65)
  - Guggenheim Foundation, 1955-63 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - "H" general, 1922-62, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 67-68)
  - Hagstrom, Jack, 1961-63 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Hale, Nancy, 1952-64, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Halévy, Daniel, 1910-50 (Box 3, Folder 71-73)
  - Halévy, Marianne, 1912-26, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Hamp, Pierre, 1949, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Hand, Learned and Frances, 1926-59 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Harper's Magazine, 1928-44 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Henderson, Joseph L., 1943-61, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 78-79)
    Related Archival Materials note
    See also: Box 12, folder 293
  - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1926-27 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Holt, Rinehart and Winston, 1957-60 (Box 3, Folder 81-82)
  - Howard, Sidney, 1917-19 (Box 3, Folder 83-85)
  - Howard, Sidney, 1920-28, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 86-87)
  - Howard, Sidney--typescripts of letters, 1917-28, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Howe, Mark De Wolfe, 1949-55 (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - Howell, Mary, 1935-63, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 90-92)
  - Hoyt, Henry M., 1918-19 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Hughes, Langston, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - Huntington Hartford Foundation, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - "I" and "J" general, 1939-61, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 96)
  - James, William, 1909 (Box 4, Folder 97)
  - Jones Library, 1956-62 (Box 4, Folder 98)
  - Jung, Carl Gustav, 1931-56 (Box 4, Folder 99)
  - See also: Woolf, Toni
  - "K" general, 1926-61, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 100)
  - Kabak, Robert, 1959-60 (Box 4, Folder 101)
  - Kendall, George, 1955-64 (Box 4, Folder 102)
    See also: MacDowell Colony, Box 5, folder 123
  - Knopf, Alfred A., Inc., 1923-61 (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - "L" general, 1927-62 (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - Lanux, Pierre de, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 105)
  - Laski, Harold, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 106)
  - Lippincott, J. B. and Co., 1945-62 (Box 4, Folder 107-08)
  - Lippmann, Walter, 1919, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 109)
  - Long, Haniel, 1929-56, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 110-14)
  - Lowell, Amy, 1916-24, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 115-17)
  - Luhan, Mabel Dodge, 1923-45, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 118)
  - "M" general, 1931-64, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 119)
  - McBride, Katherine, 1954-63 (Box 5, Folder 120)
  - McCord, David, 1959-64, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 121)
  - MacDowell, Marian, 1950-56 (Box 5, Folder 122)
  - MacDowell Colony, 1951-63 (Box 5, Folder 123)
  - MacIver, Ethel, 1962-64, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 124)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 125)
  - MacVeigh, David, 1956-61 (Box 5, Folder 126)
  - Marian, John, 1951-62 (Box 5, Folder 127)
  - Mastin, Florence Ripley, 1962-64 (Box 5, Folder 128)
  - Mencken, H. L., 1927-33, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 129)
  - Moore, Marianne, 1953-54 (Box 5, Folder 130)
  - Moore, Merrill, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 131)
  - Morrison, Kay, 1954-64 (Box 5, Folder 132)
  - Muirhead, Helen, 1920-41, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 133)
  - Myers, Elizabeth, 1946-54 (Box 5, Folder 134)
  - "N" general, 1954-63 (Box 5, Folder 135)
  - Norduff, Paul, 1954-62, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 136)
  - Oertley, Alda, 1943-61, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 137-41)
  - O'Neill, Carlotta Monterey, 1928-46 (Box 5, Folder 142-43)
  - O'Neill, Eugene, 1926-46 (Box 5, Folder 144)
  - Openhym, Evelyn, 1954-63 (Box 5, Folder 145)
  - Otis, Raymond, 1934-39, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 146)
  - "P" general, 1918-63, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 147)
  - Parsons, Alice, 1921 (Box 6, Folder 148)
  - Pearson, Ethel, 1955, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 149)
    See also: Box 14, folder 331
  - Peterkin, Julia, 1922-53, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 150)
  - Pierpont Morgan Library, 1954-63 (Box 6, Folder 151)
  - Poor, Bessie, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 152)
  - Powys, Littleton, 1947-53 (Box 6, Folder 153)
  - "R" general, 1914-62, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 154)
  - Raphael, Alice, 1929, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 155)
  - Rattner, Abraham and Esther, 1953-56, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 156)
  - Rawlings, Marjorie Kinnan, 1933-34 (Box 6, Folder 157)
  - Roberts, Elizabeth Madox, 1929-32, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 158)
  - Robinson, Edward Arlington, 1928-29 (Box 6, Folder 159)
  - Rolland, Romain, 1922 (Box 6, Folder 160)
  - Romig, Edna Davis, 1963-64, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 161)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1903 (Box 6, Folder 162)
  - Russell, Ada, 1921-29 (Box 6, Folder 163)
  - Ryan, Marjorie Rose, 1952-58, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 164-65)
  - "S" general, 1926-64, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 166-67)
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1927, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 168)
  - Sergeant, Charles Spencer, 1916-19, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 169-71)
  - Shevky, Marian, 1949-62, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 172)
  - Simpson, John L., 1956-64 (Box 6, Folder 173)
  - Spire, André and Thérèse, 1915-60, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 174-75)
  - Stableford, Nancy, and family (Box 6, Folder 176)
  - Sward, Bob and Diane, 1961-64 (Box 6, Folder 177)
  - Swenson, May, 1953-64, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 178)
  - "T" general, 1929-63 (Box 7, Folder 179)
  - Talma, Louise, 1953-61, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 180)
  - Tarbell, Ida, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 181)
  - Temple, Maud, 1910, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 182)
  - Tennant, Stephen, 1961, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 183)
  - Thayer, Ellen, 1954-64, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 184-85)
  - Torrey, Norman L., 1955-56 (Box 7, Folder 186)
  - Undset, Sigrid, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 187)
  - University of Nebraska Press, 1962-63 (Box 7, Folder 188)
  - Untermeyer, Jean Starr, 1957-63, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 189)
  - "V" general, 1920-56 (Box 7, Folder 190)
  - Van Doren, Mark and Irita, 1938-56 (Box 7, Folder 191)
  - "W" general, 1927-63, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 192)
  - Ward, Theodora, 1956-62 (Box 7, Folder 193)
  - Wells, Carlton, 1956-64 (Box 7, Folder 194)
  - Wescott, Glenway, 1927-65, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 195-96)
  - Whicher, Harriet, 1956-65, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 197)
  - White, E. B. and Katherine, 1936-63, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 198)
  - White, William Allen, 1926-42, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 199)
  - Wickes, Frances G., 1955-61, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 200)
  - Wilder, Isabel, 1954-63, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 201)
  - Wilder, Thornton, 1928-63, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 202-06)
  - Wilson, Edmund, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 207)
  - Winnick, Harriet, 1959-61 (Box 8, Folder 208)
  - Winters, Janet Lewis, 1925-62, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 209)
  - Woolf, Toni, 1932-37 (Box 8, Folder 210)
  - Young, Stark, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 211)
  - Ziegler, Joanna, 1955-56, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 212)
  - Zimmer, Henry R., n.d. (Box 8, Folder 213)
  - Unidentified, 1920-65, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 214-17)
  - Empty envelopes, 1919-65, n.d. (Box 8a, Folder 217a-f)
- Writings, 1910-63; Series II; 2; (5 boxes)
  Boxes 9-13 hold Series II, Writings, which is divided into two sections, Books and Articles. The first section, Books, is arranged alphabetically by title, and material within each title has been placed in the following order: notes and outlines, drafts, discarded pages, galleys, reviews, and publicity. The articles in the second section are arranged alphabetically by subject and title; articles on miscellaneous topics can be found at the end of the section.
  - BOOKS
    - Fire under the Andes
      - Reviews, 1927, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 218-22)
    - Robert Frost: the Trial by Existence
      - Draft of Part IV, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 223-24)
      - Draft of Part V, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 225-26)
      - Discarded pages, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 227-30)
      - Book jacket, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 231)
    - Sabia
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 232-35)
      - Notebooks, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 236)
      - Outlines, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 237)
      - "Sabia and the Wild Man": notes and draft (Box 10, Folder 238-39)
      - "Book I. Young Sabia": drafts, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 240-43)
      - "Book I. Grandie. Revised": drafts (Box 10, Folder 244-45)
      - "Part II. New Mexico": notes, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 246)
      - "Part II. New Mexico": drafts, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 247-49)
      - Discarded pages, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 250-52)
    - Shadow-Shapes
      - Review, 1921 (Box 10, Folder 253)
    - Short as any Dream
      - Reviews, 1929-30, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 254-55)
    - Willa Cather: A Memoir
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 256)
      - Notebooks, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 257-58)
      - Notebooks, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 259)
      - "First draft", n.d. (Box 11, Folder 260-64)
      - "Second draft, incomplete" (Box 11, Folder 265-67)
      - Forward to 1963 edition: draft (Box 11, Folder 268)
      - Galley corrections for 1963 edition (Box 11, Folder 269)
      - Publicity and clippings, 1963, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 270)
  - ARTICLES
    - Biographical Sketches
      - "The Bearded Robeson", [1944?] (Box 11, Folder 271)
      - "Eleanor Bertine", n.d. (Box 11, Folder 272)
      - "Henry Martyn Hoyt": typescript and
        - printed, [1918]
      - "Henry Varnum Poor": notes and (Box 11, Folder 273)
        - typescript, n.d.
      - "Portrait of John Collier": (Box 11, Folder 274)
        - typescript, [1933]
      - "The Story of Robert Flaherty", n.d. (Box 11, Folder 275)
      - "Zimmer's American Avatar", n.d. (Box 11, Folder 276)
    - Book Reviews
      - A-W (Box 12, Folder 277-78)
    - France
      - "Arles from a Convent", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 279)
      - "Fréderic Mistral": Century, 1915 Jul (Box 12, Folder 280)
      - "Guillaume", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 281)
      - "Maurice Barrés": New Republic, 1914 Dec (Box 12, Folder 282)
      - "M. le Curé's Lunch Party": Century, 1915 Dec
      - "The Other Side of the Door: Century, n.d.
      - "A Peasant Hero of Provence", n.d.
      - "Provençal Verse of Henri Fabre": New Republic, 1915 Jan
      - "Standards of a Bourgeois Family"
    - New Mexico
      - "Christmas in the Pueblo": Survey Graphic, 1923 Dec (Box 12, Folder 283)
      - "The Journal of a Mud Hut": Harper's Magazine, 1922 Mar
      - "Mary Austin: A Portrait", [1934] (Box 12, Folder 284)
      - "New Mexico Writers": New Mexico Sentinel, 1938 Oct
      - "The Santa Fe Group": Saturday Review, 1934 Dec
      - "Sphinx of Taos Desert": Saturday Review, [1938] (Box 12, Folder 285)
      - "The Writers' New Mexico", n.d.
    - Popular Psychology
      - "Five Are Gone", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 286)
      - "Getting Along with the Young", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 287)
      - "Help Wanted": McCall's, 1932 Apr
      - "How Old is a Woman in her Sixties?", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 288)
      - "I Chose Not to be an Invalid", n.d.
      - "Jung of Zurich", [1939] (Box 12, Folder 289)
      - "Men and Marriage", [1940] (Box 12, Folder 290)
      - "Must Great Women be Ruthless?", n.d.
      - "Portrait of Dr. Jung": typescript and galleys, 1930 (Box 12, Folder 291-92)
      - "Problems of the Older Woman", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 293)
      - "The Soldier and his Wife"
      - "Today's Approach to Marriage", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 294)
      - "What can a Married Man do about the
        - Other Woman?", n.d.
      - "What do You Want?", [1933]
      - "What Doctor Jung Thinks about (Box 12, Folder 295)
        - Marriage", n.d.
    - World War I
      - Articles for The New Republic, 1915-19, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 296-98)
      - "Above the Valley", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 299)
      - "Army Schools and Corps Schools"
      - "La Belle France", n.d.
      - "Drawing the Picture", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 300)
      - "The Training of the Army", n.d.
      - "The Woman's Share of It", n.d.
      - Fragments, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 301)
    - Miscellaneous Articles
      - "Educated for What?": New Republic, 1916 Jan (Box 13, Folder 302)
      - "Good Old New England Cooking" (Box 13, Folder 303)
      - "In Chains": McClure's, 1911 (Box 13, Folder 304)
      - " Quid Pro Quo ": New Republic, 1920 May
      - "The Stay-With", n.d.
      - "This I Believe", [1952?] (Box 13, Folder 305)
      - "Toilers of the Tenements": McClure's, 1910 Jul (Box 13, Folder 306)
      - "What's in a Pagoda?": New Republic, 1916 Apr
      - Fragments and notebooks (Box 13, Folder 307)
- Subject Files, 1913-65; Series III; 1.75; (4 boxes)
  Series III, Subject Files, is contained in Boxes 14-17 and is alphabetically arranged by subject and then by type of material.
  - Austin, Mary: obituary, 1934 (Box 14, Folder 308)
  - Cather, Willa, 1941-52, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 309)
  - Collier, John: writings and other papers, 1930-57, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 310-11)
  - Copeland, Charles Townsend, 1926, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 312)
  - Frost, Robert, 1961, n.d (Box 14, Folder 313)
  - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1931-48, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 314)
  - Howard, Sidney, 1918, 1939, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 315)
  - Hoyt, Henry Martyn: obituaries, 1921 (Box 14, Folder 316)
  - Jung, Carl Gustav
    - Notes and papers, 1931-34, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 317)
    - Photographs, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 318)
    - Printed, 1945-63 (Box 14, Folder 319)
    - Writings, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 320)
  - Lawrence, D. H.: newspaper clippings, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 321)
  - Long, Haniel, 1936-65, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 322)
  - Lowell, Amy: newspaper clippings, 1927-28 (Box 14, Folder 323)
  - McCord, David, 1960, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 324)
  - Masson, André, 1942-45, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 325)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Newspaper clippings, 1921-63, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 326-27)
    - Papers, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 328)
    - Printed, 1930-65, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 329-30)
  - Miss Winsor's School
    - Correspondence A-D, 1952-57 (Box 14, Folder 331-33)
    - Correspondence E-W, 1952-57 (Box 15, Folder 334-41)
    - Draft notes, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 342-46)
    - Index cards to draft (Box 15, Folder 347-48)
    - "Mary Picard Winsor": typescript, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 349)
    - Papers: "Frederic Winsor, 1829-1889", n.d. (Box 15, Folder 350)
    - Papers: "Miss Winsor's Speech", 1936 (Box 15, Folder 351)
    - Printed, 1941-53, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 352-53)
  - Mistral, Frédéric: notes and printed, 1913, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 354-55)
  - O'Neill, Eugene and Carlotta
    - Newspaper clippings, 1926-53, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 356-57)
    - Notes and interview transcripts, 1946-53, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 358)
    - Photographs, 1946, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 359)
    - Printed, 1953, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 360)
  - Peterkin, Julia: notes, writings, clippings, 1927, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 361)
  - Powys, Llewellyn
    - Letters 1919-39: mimeograph, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 362-68)
    - Photographs, 1925-39, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 369)
  - Robeson, Paul, 1943-44 (Box 17, Folder 370)
  - Romig, Edna Davis, 1952-63 (Box 17, Folder 371)
  - Salmon, Thomas W.
    - Correspondence about, 1927-42, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 372)
    - Notes, 1922, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 373)
    - Obituaries, 1927-28 (Box 17, Folder 374)
    - Writings, 1922-26, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 375)
  - Spire, André
    - Correspondence about, 1941-44 (Box 17, Folder 376)
    - Papers, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 377)
    - Printed, 1944, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 378)
    - Writings, 1941-48, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 379)
  - Sward, Robert: poetry, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 380)
  - Swenson, May, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 381)
  - White, William Allen, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 382)
  - Wilder, Thornton: printed, 1958-62 (Box 17, Folder 383)
  - Wolff, Toni: photographs, 1929, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 384)
  - Zimmer, Henry R.
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 385)
    - Photographs and writings, 1942-44, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 386)
- Personal Papers, 1910-65; Series IV; 0.75; (2 boxes)
  Two boxes hold Series IV, Personal Papers, which have been arranged alphabetically by subject or type of material.
  - Address books, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 387)
  - Biographical sketches and resumés, 1929-63, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 388-89)
  - Bryn Mawr
    - Citation, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 390)
    - Fiftieth reunion, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 391)
    - Printed, 1928, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 392)
  - Contracts and copyrights, 1916-48 (Box 18, Folder 393)
  - Family history and reminiscences (Box 18, Folder 394-95)
  - France
    - Provence, 1910-13, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 396-97)
    - World War I, 1918 (Box 18, Folder 398)
  - Guggenheim Fellowship: application, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 399)
  - MacDowell Colony: photographs, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 400)
  - MacDowell Colony: printed, 1957-63, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 401)
  - Miscellaneous papers, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 402)
  - Miscellaneous printed, 1912-60, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 403-04)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1927-63 (Box 19, Folder 405)
  - Notebooks, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 406-07)
  - Obituaries, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 408)
  - Obituary tributes, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 409)
  - Passport, 1918 (Box 19, Folder 410)
  - Photographs, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 411)
  - Royalty statements, 1921-32 (Box 19, Folder 412)
- Restricted Fragile Papers
  Conditions Governing Access
  Boxes 21-22: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Restricted Fragile Papers from Box 1, folder 3 to Box 9, folder 230. (Box 20)
  - Restricted Fragile Papers from Box 9, folder 233 to Box 19, folder 405. (Box 21)